# **Gautham Thirunavakkarasu**

thi.gautham@outlook.com | (469) 432-5281

#### **ABOUT ME**

**Professional Interests** 

Data science, machine learning research, deep learning, statistics and data visualization.

**Technical Skills** 

Python (TensorFlow, scikit-learn, pandas, numpy, etc.), RStudio, Jupyter Notebook, MATLAB, git and others. Experienced in data visualization libraries such as ggplot2, pyplot, seaborn and others. Engineering modelling and simulations in CATIA V5, ANSYS, IcePak and others. Familiar with AWS, Talend and Salesforce. Experienced in Agile, Functional data analysis and Process design and development.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## PUBLICIS SAPIENT, Global Project Delivery,

San Francisco, CA (Jan 2020 – Present)

**Associate Technology** 

- Develop data-driven insights to identify process design improvements; collaborate with stakeholders to operationalize opportunities and develop strategies for scaling development.
- \*Wrangle data from multiple sources (open data orgs and legacy government data systems using Python and R to develop KPI's and use cases which leveraged to setup Data Governance and data cleansing process utilizing ETL tools such as Talend.
- Designing user-centered processes and product features focused ease of use through technical research and in-depth data analysis.
- ❖Successfully lead team of 4 directs and managed numerous time critical project deliveries on time.

### ASTA CRS Inc, Technical Consultant

San Francisco, CA (Jan 2019 – Jan 2020)

- Served as the Functional Lead with the responsibility of business process ownership for solution implementation and collaborating multi-competency teams of data engineers, developers, solution architects and business analysts.
- A focus on educating project stakeholders and legacy system SME's into Agile methodology and bringing about Digital Busines Transformation for a government office.

EMNSPC LAB, Graduate Research Assistant,

Arlington, TX (Jun 2016 - Nov 2018)

Amazon, Product Analyst

Bangalore, IN (Dec 2015- May 2016)

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science, Mechanical Engineering University of Texas at Arlington Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Engineering Visvesvaraya Technological University Arlington, TX (May 2018)

Bangalore, IN (July 2015)

## PERSONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS & PROJECTS

"Attribute Recognition in Residential Properties for Valuation assessment" –Built a CNN feature extraction model based on building plans submitted to the county Assessor Office.

ent San

San Francisco, CA (Apr 2020)

"Sales Insight on residential and commercial property" – Built a valuation assessment model leveraging predictive analysis and presented solution to the Deputy Assessor of San Mateo County.

San Francisco, CA (June 2020)

Certified ScrumMaster (CSM), Scrum Alliance

Mountain View, CA (Jan 2020)

Outstanding Teamwork & Publics Service Award – Global Project Delivery Team, Assessor Property Assessment System Team <add github link> San Francisco, CA (Dec 2019)

G.Thirunavakkarasu and et all, "Air flow pattern and path flow simulation of airborne particulate contaminants in Cold aisle containment high-density data center using air-side economization"; Paper No: IPACK2018-8436, V001T02A011; <add link >

San Francisco, CA (Aug 2018)